Empires are built on fear. Rebellions are built on hope.
Rogue One: A Star Wars Story is a action, adventure,
science fiction film directed by Gareth Edwards.
A rogue band of resistance fighters unite for a mission to steal the
Death Star plans and bring a new hope to the galaxy.
Jyn Erso, played by Felicity Jones.
Cassian Andor, played by Diego Luna.
K-2SO, played by Alan Tudyk.
Chirrut Imwe, played by Donnie Yen.
Baze Malbus, played by Jiang Wen.
Orson Krennic, played by Ben Mendelsohn.
Rogue One: A Star Wars Story is a 2016 American epic space opera film directed
by Gareth Edwards and written by Chris Weitz and Tony Gilroy.
Produced by Lucasfilm and distributed by Walt Disney Studios Motion Pictures, it is
the first Star Wars anthology film and a prequel to Star Wars (1977).
It stars Felicity Jones, Diego Luna, Ben Mendelsohn, Donnie Yen, Mads
Mikkelsen, Alan Tudyk, Riz Ahmed, Jiang Wen, and Forest Whitaker.
Set a week before the events of Star Wars, Rogue One follows rebels who steal the
schematics for the Galactic Empire's ultimate weapon, the Death Star.
It details the Rebel Alliance's first effective victory against the
Empire, as referenced in the Star Wars opening crawl.
John Knoll, who served as the visual effects supervisor of the Star Wars prequel trilogy, pitched Rogue
One's story as an episode of the unproduced television series Star Wars: Underworld in 2003.
He pitched it again as a film following Disney's acquisition of
Lucasfilm in 2012; Edwards was hired to direct in 2014.
Edwards sought to differentiate Rogue One from previous Star Wars films and approach it as a war film, omitting
the opening crawl and transitional screen wipes used in the main "Skywalker Saga" installments.
Principal photography began at Pinewood Studios, Buckinghamshire,
in early August 2015 and wrapped in February 2016.
The film went through extensive reshoots in mid-2016.
The score was composed by Michael Giacchino, rather than
the Skywalker Saga composer John Williams.
With an estimated production budget of $200–280.2 million, Rogue
One is one of the most expensive films ever made.
Rogue One: A Star Wars Story premiered in Los Angeles on December 10, 2016, and
was theatrically released in the United States on December 16.
It received positive reviews, with praise for its acting, story, visuals, musical score, cinematography, and darker tone than
previous Star Wars films, but criticism for its pacing and digital recreations of Carrie Fisher and Peter Cushing.
Rogue One grossed $1 billion worldwide, becoming the second-highest-grossing film of 2016, and
received two Academy Award nominations for Best Sound Mixing and Best Visual Effects.
Andor, a prequel television series, aired on the streaming
service Disney+ for two seasons from 2022 to 2025.
The film explores themes of rebellion, spacecraft,
rebel, space battle, space travel.
The tone is thought_provoking.